Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/haagjohanna (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Redaktion

Public Relations

Französisch

Languages

Französisch (Full Professional)
Englisch (Full Professional)
Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Publications

Zivilgesellschaftliches Engagement kennt keine Grenzen

Johanna Haag

Communications for buergerfonds.eu / fondscitoyen.eu | 30u30 Crew 2021

Paris

Zusammenfassung

After my studies in Mannheim and Paris and several experiences in the fields of journalism, media education, corporate publishing and PR in France and Germany, I am currently working in a challenging job that allows me to advance my strategic thinking and exploit my editorial and communicational skills in an international work environment. I'm happy to be contributing to an inspiring team, while taking responsibilities and every opportunity to grow on a professional and personal level.

To get to know me better, have a look at my Twitter @cestjohanna or send me a message.

Berufserfahrung

Deutsch-Französischer Bürgerfonds | Fonds citoyen franco-allemand Communications Manager

Mai 2020 - Present (1 Jahr 11 Monate)

Paris, Île-de-France, France

Building and implementing the communications strategy, being in charge of all channels: PR, Social Media, Newsletter, website, ...

OFAJ DFJW

1 Jahr 8 Monate

Press Relations Officer Oktober 2018 - Mai 2020 (1 Jahr 8 Monate)

Paris und Umgebung, Frankreich

Deputy Head of Division "Communication and Events" Oktober 2019 - März 2020 (6 Monate)

Paris und Umgebung, Frankreich

While replacing my manager during her maternity leave, I was managing a team of 7 people in Paris and Berlin, being in charge of the whole

communication team: press relations, social media, web, publications and the translation unit.

Handelsblatt

Freelance Editor (for orange by handelsblatt) April 2017 - März 2019 (2 Jahre)

Düsseldorf und Umgebung, Deutschland

As a freelance correspondant for Handelsblatt's youth offer "orange by handelsblatt" I covered news topics from Paris.

ARTE

Project manager (internship at Educ'ARTE by Arte France Développement) April 2018 - September 2018 (6 Monate)

Paris

At Educ'ARTE, a digital video library and the educational offer of the German-French TV-channel ARTE, I was mainly in charge of the video catalogue (editing, translation, indexation, ...) and community management on the newly created Twitter account.

ZEIT ONLINE

Editor (internship at ZEIT Campus ONLINE)
Juni 2017 - August 2017 (3 Monate)
Berlin

At ZEIT Campus ONLINE, the magazine for young adults by ZEIT ONLINE, one of Germany's leading online newspapers, I wrote articles, conducted interviews, edited freelancers' work, did research and participated in the development of new formats.

Open2Europe

Corporate PR consultant (internship/junior consultant) März 2016 - September 2016 (7 Monate)

Asnières-sur-Seine, F

At Open2Europe, a Paris based PR-agency with European scope and trilingual work environment (French, English, German), I worked for international clients in the fields of household appliances (Haier), tourism (Voyages-sncf.com), fashion (Eric Bompard) and others: press releases / kits / invitations / trips, translation, reporting, on-site-coordination of press relations at International Consumer Fair IFA, ...

OFAJ DFJW

Institutional PR consultant (internship) März 2015 - September 2015 (7 Monate) Paris. F

At OFAJ / DFJW, the French-German Youth Office, I supported the press relations in drafting press releases / kits / invitations, translating, doing monitoring, accompagning an international press trip; I also wrote articles for the corporate magazine.

OPHELIAS Culture PR
Cultural PR consultant (internship)
August 2014 - Februar 2015 (7 Monate)
München

At OPHELIAS, a PR-agency for artists and cultural institutions, I monitored the press, wrote press releases, accompagnied artists & journalists and created Social Media postings.

Mannheimer Morgen Großdruckerei & Verlag GmbH Editor & editor-in-chief of the "university" section (freelance) September 2012 - August 2014 (2 Jahre) Mannheim

At the "university" section of Mannheim's local newspaper, I wrote articles about university & students topics, conducted interviews, layouted the newspaper page, was in charge of the topic planning and coordinated the editorial staff.

SIGNUM communication Werbeagentur GmbH Editor (internship) Juni 2013 - August 2013 (3 Monate) Mannheim

At SIGNUM, a corporate publishing agency, I wrote portraits, articles, news ... for corporate journals, conducted interviews and did background research.

Weißenburger Tagblatt Editor (internship) Mai 2011 - Juni 2011 (2 Monate) Weißenburg i. Bay.

At the local newspaper of my hometown I wrote articles, event reports, news, announcements ..., conducted background research and interviews and edited texts.

Ausbildung

Université Paris 8

Master, Culture et communication: Industries culturelles et créatives - $MCube \cdot (2017 - 2018)$

Université Vincennes-Saint-Denis (Paris VIII)

Master, Culture et communication: Médias internationaux - enjeux et pratiques · (2016 - 2017)

Universität Mannheim

 $\label{eq:Bachelor} \text{Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Media and communication science};$

French · (2011 - 2015)

Université Sorbonne Nouvelle - Paris 3

Information et communication · (2013 - 2013)